[ Watch on kissFlix.co ]
9 YEARS LATER
THE BLUE HOUSE, 1979
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
[President Park] Deputy Director Baek.
Hello, sir.
That's right. I'm Baek Kitae.
The deputy director of
the Korean Central Intelligence Agency.
So… [sighs]
…how long have I been in this chair?
Almost… two decades.
And that's far too long for this job,
isn't it?
Absolutely not.
[chuckles] Yes, it is.
That's why there's been such a…
strident outcry.
Don't worry about that.
People love to raise their voices.
They'll all stop soon.
On a separate subject,
the way Director Cho's been
looking at me lately, well…
it's different now.
What's your opinion? You agree?
Busan's dealing with the protests.
I'd say that's putting him
in a tough position.
President Park's left and right hands:
Director Cho of the KCIA and Chief Gwak
of the Presidential Security Service.
On the surface, they claim to be searching
for a solution to the unrest in Busan.
But the truth is they're competing
for the president's favor
and their share of the pie.
The Yushin regime is autocratic
and tyrannical.
That's what all the protestors are saying.
[Kitae] And then there's Cheon Seokjung,
Park's Chief of Staff,
and the second-most powerful man
in the country right now.
Look, I'm sure they have their reasons.
What?
Things will only get worse if we decide
to suppress the demonstrations by force.
See what I mean? The KCIA has
gone too damn soft for my taste.
It's giving these commie protestors
whatever they want.
I say let's just roll some tanks in there.
And you, shut your mouth.
What'd you say to me, you asshole? Huh?
Come on, that's enough.
Don't be so vulgar.
Oh, I think you heard me.
Asshole!
Hey, hey, cool it. Let's be civil here.
-You little shit.
-[Gwak chuckling] Whoa, here we go.
-Have you lost your damn mind or what?
-Excuse me?
You really want to push me over the line,
you asshole?
You know, swearing won't fix the country.
-[grunting] How dare you…
-[grunting]
-I'm gonna crush you…
[Cho] Think you can get cocky
just 'cause the president's backing you?
[Gwak] Think you're better than me,
you piece of shit?
Cho's become too soft.
The KCIA needs to crack down harder.
-Don't you think?
-Absolutely, sir.
Stick as close as you can to Cho.
Keep an eye on him, my friend.
-[knock on door]
-Yes, sir.
[door opens]
Mr. President, Madam Shin is here.
Ah, there you are.
Glad you could make it, Madam Shin.
I was feeling a little unsettled
after a strange dream.
[clicks tongue]
By the way, this is Baek Kitae,
the man I told you about.
He's the deputy director of the KCIA.
Introduce yourself.
Baek Kitae, madam.
You're very handsome.
I'm Madam Shin.
[♪ intriguing music playing]
STYLE
::cue()
You have such lovely hands too.
[in Japanese] I can see why
you treasure him so dearly, sir.
He'll lead this country
as the next KCIA director.
[in English] At your service!
[in Japanese] Thank you!
[in English] Oh, wow.
So you speak a little Japanese as well?
I lived in Osaka for a while.
Ah, Osaka.
Very nice.
All right, Baek, keep a close watch
on Cho and report to me regularly.
Of course, sir!
I think it's time to go in, Madam Shin.
'Cause I'm getting impatient.
All right, let's go.
[softly] So I'll be the director?
[chuckles]
[♪ theme music playing]
[Cho] That son of a bitch
has gone insane, I swear.
[door opens]
[Cho] He's not gonna get away with this.
[breathing heavily]
-Good afternoon, Director.
-Gonna smash his smug little face in.
That bastard is dead.
I'm gonna tear him to little pieces.
What's the matter?
Baek, listen. You trust me?
Of course, sir, completely.
Good. Trust only me.
One day, I'll end all of this.
That's the only way we'll survive.
I don't know what you mean by that.
"Life's a long journey.
It's so easy to be led astray.
But if a man's determined
to walk his path,
any storm can be weathered.
He'll make his own way."
Have a good day.
[person] Ah, good aftern… What the…
Deputy Director Baek, good afternoon.
[Kitae] Major General Hwang Daesik,
leader of the Military Security Command.
He's known Cheon Seokjung,
the president's favorite advisor,
since their days
at the Korean Military Academy.
But even so, Hwang's been gunning
for Cheon's position for a long time.
STYLE
::cue()
Are you here for the president?
I have something I need to report.
[♪ intriguing music playing]
Busan keeping you busy lately?
Those bastards. They love to riot
like animals, that's all it is.
After everything the president's done
to better this country,
suddenly a bunch of ungrateful protestors
are whining about terms limits.
And no mention of Kim Ilsung
who's been making himself a god
for the last 30 years. [clicks tongue]
Democracy?
Do these morons even know
what that word means?
Pampered sons of bitches.
Why don't we just round them up quick
and lop off their heads one by one?
Why don't you and I get a drink sometime?
Why not tonight?
First round's on me.
-Sorry, tonight is no good.
-Ah. [laughs]
Well, I'm gonna hold you to it.
I'll see you around, Mr. Baek. [chuckles]
[sighing] That little bastard.
I should just…
Geez.
Hwang Daesik went
to the president's office?
Yes. It seems the president's been
taking an interest in him lately.
CHIEF OF STAFF TO THE PRESIDENT
CHEON SEOKJUNG
Inviting him to drinks and all that.
Wow, that jackass.
Baek, I think… [sighs]
…we should teach that prick
a lesson while we can.
What do you have in mind?
Why don't you come up with something?
We need to humble him…
before he gets too big for his britches.
[Kitae] Chief Cheon has wielded
absolute power for over a decade,
but even so, he's always
playing second fiddle to the president.
By the way… [sighs]
…you know how disappointed
the president was
with the last election, right?
Are you talking about the campaign funds?
[lighter flicks open]
This time we need to make sure
we have a sizeable war chest.
Sir, I gathered all the resources
I could back then.
Kitae, listen.
I'm not making this request
out of self-interest.
[Kitae sighs]
This is all about
planting enough allies, all right?
We need people
in the National Assembly. Hey.
You know why the president
favors Daesik these days?
[Kitae exhales deeply]
He tests your loyalty from time to time,
that much I know.
So maybe…
he's trying to toughen you up
and make your skin thicker
before he steps down
and hands his seat to you.
[laughing]
Kitae, Kitae…
You still don't know him at all.
That man has absolutely
no intention of stepping down. Ever.
Don't you get it?
It's because of me.
He's got Hwang Daesik
glued to his hip to keep me in check.
His time's running out, though.
He's not as sharp as he was.
STYLE
::cue()
[car horns honking]
[♪ classical music playing on stereo]
Tell me, Kihun.
[Kihun] Yes, sir.
You've been working with me how long now?
Seven or eight years, I think?
Ever since you moved to Seoul.
Your accent's just as obvious
as it was then.
[Kihun] I've been doing my best, sir.
Is it that easy to tell?
I mean, what do you think?
I'm sorry, sir. I'll try harder.
That's not why I asked.
When do the materials from Taiwan arrive?
Should be here by Sunday, sir.
[Kitae] Make sure to run the lab
day and night
to hit the volume we need.
[Kihun] Understood.
By the way, sir,
do you mind if…
I ask you something about the business?
What is it?
Well, wouldn't we…
wouldn't we increase profits…
if we sold our product here in Korea too?
Exports are important,
but the local market--
-Kihun.
-Uh, yes, sir?
If you don't want to die,
focus on driving.
Yes, I apologize.
Why would we push drugs
in this beautiful country?
Don't forget…
what we do is for patriotism.
For our nation.
Yes, of course. Our nation.
[Kitae sighs]
What a gorgeous day.
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
-[forklift beeping]
-[whistle blowing]
[vocalizing]
[scatting]
Well, well, well. Here we are.
That was quick.
[worker] Bring it this way! More, more.
-Changbae.
-Yeah?
Can you hear the sound
of money rolling in?
[Changbae] Oh, yeah.
I hear it loud and clear.
-Pick up the pace! Move it!
-[chuckles]
OSAKA, JAPAN
[Ikeda, in Japanese] Thank you for coming.
There's one simple reason
I called you all here today.
As you all know by now…
my health is failing rather quickly.
Which means that…
remaining in this position
would only reflect…
my own arrogance.
No…
More like excessive greed on my part.
Please, Kumicho.
I urge you to reconsider.
STYLE
::cue()
[all] Please reconsider!
[Kitae, in Korean] Choi Yuji has been
biding her time with her head down
and her claws retracted.
She's waited a while for this moment.
[in Japanese] The Ikeda clan…
must not take its current prosperity
for granted.
No complacency.
We must keep rebuilding…
through strong reforms
that bolster the foundation we built.
At the next general meeting,
I will announce my successor,
and my decision will be final.
[Kitae, in Korean] But no matter
how shrewd and capable she is,
clan leadership would
never willingly accept
a young female Zainichi
as the official successor.
[Kimura, in Japanese] Understood, sir.
If that's what our kumicho
intends for the future…
we will follow you and obey your will.
[all, in Japanese] We will follow it!
[Kitae, in Korean] If she has any hope
of claiming that seat and rising to power,
her first step is to overcome
this man: Kimura Yoichi.
[Harimoto, in Japanese]
You wanted to talk?
[Yuji] I'll get straight to the point.
I want your assistance
with the succession, Harimoto.
[Harimoto scoffs]
Kimura's conservative and old-fashioned.
Under him, the clan will stagnate.
Who knows, it may even wither away.
You know that, don't you?
Well, the fact remains.
It's very possible
that your father will choose him.
[bird chirping]
[Yuji] Don't worry. Leave that to me.
The real question is,
what happens in a power vacuum?
Harimoto, if you and I were
to collaborate,
don't you think we might prevail?
[sighs]
[in Korean] I heard your brother was
arrested in Korea for foreign espionage.
You know I have ties
with the KCIA, don't you?
If you want… I'll make sure he gets out.
In Korea, espionage
gets you the death penalty.
So, then, will you really take over
this clan as kumicho?
[chuckling]
[Kitae] Yuji's lifelong dream has
been to lead the clan as kumicho.
She'd do anything to be in control.
Professor Jang Gyeongsik?
[Yuji] He's the brother
of our regional boss, Harimoto.
I mentioned him before, right?
He runs our Tokyo operation.
He's a Zainichi, like me.
Kimura's one of the old guard,
from the main family…
but Harimoto would be a big help to me.
Kimura could be swayed by that.
After all, Harimoto has
a major stake in the clan,
and his influence runs deep.
What exactly do you need from me, then?
[bird chirping]
Professor Jang Gyeongsik went
to Korea to visit his ancestral graves,
and got himself arrested.
STYLE
::cue()
For espionage.
So you're asking me to get him out.
DEPUTY DIRECTOR BAEK KITAE
Think you could pull some strings?
And if I do? What then?
They won't have to announce a successor.
And I can help my father get some rest.
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
BUSAN, KOREA
[♪ classical music playing on stereo]
[car horns honking]
[honking continues]
You know, I expected it
to be more chaotic.
Heard they burned down a TV station.
You're right.
It is quiet.
[Kihun] What's with the traffic?
Was there an accident?
-[loud boom, hiss]
-[people clamoring]
-[protester 1] Over there! They're coming!
-[Kihun] Whoa.
-[whistles blowing]
-[Kihun] What's going on?
[bystander exclaims]
-[people clamoring]
-[glass shattering]
-[car rattles]
-[Kihun] Whoa.
[clamoring continues]
[protester 2] Get off him!
[Kihun] Oh, geez.
-[clamoring continues]
-[glass breaking]
[protester 3 crying out]
[soldier grunts] You crazy bitch!
All right. That's it. You're dead.
[♪ classical music continues]
KCIA BUSAN BRANCH
[person wailing, screaming]
-[blows landing]
-[person screaming]
-[blows continue]
-[screaming continues]
[agent] Hold still!
[victim] No, please, don't!
No, please, please!
[groaning, screaming]
[screaming]
Hey!
[victim panting, groaning]
Sir.
[victim panting, coughing]
[victims breathing heavily]
[victims groaning, whimpering]
[grunting]
STYLE
::cue()
[♪ jazz music playing]
Deputy Director.
I can't imagine you have much free time.
So what brings you down to Busan, sir?
You really don't have to be polite,
it's just us.
The formality's uncomfortable.
[Haksu] Well, I didn't want
to be inappropriate, sir.
I'm just a lowly branch director general,
and you're the KCIA's second-in-command.
So I can't really be candid unless…
you want me to.
And it sounds like you do?
Don't you?
You got a toupee?
So you noticed?
[laughs]
Can't keep my damn hair for some reason.
I think it's this job.
Director Hwang went bald too.
DIRECTOR GENERAL PYO HAKSU
But you haven't.
Why aren't you losing any?
That'd be a question for your father.
My old man? Right.
What's this job got to do with it?
It's all genetics.
Just have to get lucky at birth, I guess.
I saw quite a scene on the drive in.
What's the status?
It doesn't look good.
Masan's a wreck too.
There's no guarantee
it won't spread to Seoul.
Thing is, the president's
overstayed his welcome.
You're being disrespectful.
What's your deal?
Don't you think he deserves it?
You little shit. [clicks tongue]
Watch your mouth.
Yes, sir.
[Kitae sighs]
You've rounded up a sizable collection.
What can I say? Commies are coming out
of the damn woodwork these days.
Or you're creating them outta thin air.
Well, you know how it is.
The president needs
to see numbers to be persuaded,
especially since he favors the MSC
over the KCIA lately.
Those bastards just couldn't
keep their noses out of anything.
[clicks tongue]
You know what the hardest part is?
You have to keep changing the narratives.
Otherwise, people get bored
and lose interest.
So hire a novelist or something.
I already have, actually.
So what is it?
Why are you here?
I can't get into the details.
Here, this man.
I'm gonna need him, okay?
HANDLER
JANG GYEONGSIK
[all panting]
Who's Jang Gyeongsik?
Hold up your hand.
[in Japanese] Who's Jang Gyeongsik?
Raise your hand if it's you.
-Yes?
-[in English] Get him.
[all clamoring]
[Kitae] Koreans born and raised in Japan
could barely understand,
let alone resist,
South Korea's harsh anti-communist laws.
Get the cuffs!
[Kitae] Many of them
barely spoke Korean at all,
which made them easy targets
in the KCIA and the MSC's quest
to frame unsuspecting expats
for espionage.
Catching spies brought reward money,
professional perks,
special promotions,
even the president's personal favor.
So, naturally, everyone in the government
became obsessed with hunting them down.
[♪ tense music playing]
[sobbing, sniffling]
You want him released?
Bold move.
You're not worried about the director?
Are you worried about it?
Cho's pretty much finished, but… even so.
Well… [sighs]
…can you release this guy or not?
[chuckles] You give an order, I follow it.
I'm just a humble branch director general.
[grunts]
By the way,
this stuff's all over Busan right now.
I thought you said
you were only planning to export.
That you wouldn't push it in Korea.
STYLE
::cue()
-You found this here in the city?
-Mm-hmm.
There was a woman who used to work
under Jang Geonyoung, remember her?
Oh Yejin.
She's a prosecutor
at the Busan District Office now.
She's desperate to catch people
who sell that.
Word is she's a lunatic, too.
Just like Geonyoung.
She'll move heaven and earth
to get the job done.
[♪ intriguing music playing]
[dealer] Oh, yeah.
That's the number one product
going around these days.
Usually gets exported straight to Tokyo.
Once you get a taste of it,
nothing else hits the same. [chuckles]
So, uh…
how come you're here all alone today,
Miss Oh?
My guys are outside.
They were just in the way.
What about the rest?
-How much do you need?
-[exhales]
I need all of it.
As much as you've got.
[chuckles]
I'm not sure you can handle that.
[sighs]
Look, are we gonna make this deal or not?
How bad do you want it? [grunts]
I'm up for anything.
Yeah, me too.
Well, come on, then.
[laughing]
[all laughing]
You wanna do it now?
With the boys watching?
Why not?
Always better with an audience.
Oh, wait… are you serious?
All right. Yeah. Uh…
[chuckling] Aw, yeah, great.
What are you idiots looking at?
Close your eyes.
-Right, here we go.
-[moans]
[dealer breathing heavily]
Wh-wh-what are you doing? Come on.
-Don't be such a tease.
-[Yejin sighs]
[both chuckling]
-[grunts] Come on, I can't take it!
-[moans]
All right, let's get down to business.
Hey! What the hell? [exclaims]
-Goddamn it!
-[grunts]
[both grunting]
[♪ upbeat music playing]
[Yejin] Come here!
Whoa, what are you doing?
Hey, stop it! No!
-Miss Oh, you're not allowed to--
-[gunshot]
[dealer grunting]
[groans]
Who are you really?
I'm Prosecutor Oh Yejin
from the Busan District Office,
you drug-dealing sack of shit!
-One…
-[groaning]
Shut up, idiot.
-…two…
-[exclaims]
-Cut the shit, all right?
-…three,
-and four.
-Hey, asshole, stay down on your knees.
Shut up. Look at me, you prick.
Okay. Where'd you get the drugs?
[scoffs]
[Yejin] Listen, Kim.
You go back to jail, you'll be doing
a mandatory minimum of ten years.
-Understand?
-[scoffs]
Just for pushing a little meth?
-You're pulling my leg, aren't you?
-[chuckles]
-Nope.
-Argh, shit!
[groaning] Damn it!
-You know…
-Ow.
…I busted my ass for ten years
to become a prosecutor.
Why?
To throw little scumbags
like you into prison forever.
[Kim panting]
So I'd stake my badge on this.
You're so screwed.
So what's it gonna be?
Start talking
and do a year in county jail,
or get sent to prison for a decade?
[grunting]
You really wanna deal with
the other inmates every day?
[breathing heavily]
[grunts] A year.
-You give me your word?
-Oh, yeah, I got you.
It's a deal then.
So, who's supplying you?
Changbae. He runs a lab up in Seoul.
That's where they make this stuff.
And, man, it's, uh… just…
It's killer. And normally they…
they only export it to Japan, you usually
can't find it anywhere in Korea.
But he must've needed the cash.
So he came right to me.
"Changbae"?
Yeah. Park Changbae.
[sighs] Park Changbae, huh?
STYLE
::cue()
[humming, vocalizing]
[♪ gentle music playing on radio]
You're drinking before
the sun's even gone down?
Huh?
You know how bad that is for you?
Come on.
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa. Easy.
You're breaking everything.
-[scoffs]
-[chuckles]
-What are you doing?
-I'd love…
a little refill, please.
[sighs]
You're gonna put your stomach
through hell.
Oh, whatever. [grunts]
[clears throat] All right.
[grunts]
How about some food? Oh, what…
What's up with you?
Uh, what's happening?
[chuckles] You wanna?
What are you saying?
[chuckles]
-What do you think? [laughing]
-Ah! Shit.
Dumbass. Your face! [laughing]
[gasps] Oh! Uh…
Oh, my gosh.
I wasn't expecting you, Kitae.
Nobody else here?
No. We finished all the shipments,
so everyone got to head out early.
[door closes]
[Kitae sighs]
Soyeong, go get ready for the memorial.
Kihyun's going too.
Oh.
All right, I'll go. What about you?
I need to talk to Changbae first.
Okay.
[door opens, closes]
-[Kitae] Have a seat.
-Right, sure.
[radio clicks off]
[Kitae sighs]
Changbae.
Yes, sir?
What do you think is the most
essential virtue a person should have?
Love, I guess?
Love. [chuckles]
Right, love is important, sure.
Wanna know what I'd pick?
Shame would be my answer.
Shame? Really?
There's no one I hate more
than a shameless person.
Someone that's blithe
and careless in everything they do.
A shameless guy is always deferent.
He'll smile and nod
and swear he'll do anything for you.
But when it really counts,
he'll stick a knife in your back
like it's nothing.
[♪ tense music playing]
[Kitae] That's what it means…
to be shameless in this world.
And if you have no shame…
you're no different
than an animal in the wild.
Don't you think?
[Changbae breathing shakily]
[hammer cocks]
You skimming our stuff?
STYLE
::cue()
[Changbae exhales shakily]
What? I didn't take any product.
-[gun clicks]
-[breathing shakily]
Look, sir, I'm sorry.
I'm not sure we can keep working
together if you're going to do this.
I'm telling you, I didn't do anything.
All right?
Trust me, okay?
Just please, don't!
You're pushing the product in Busan.
I didn't do that. I wouldn't betray you.
-[gun clicks]
-[gasping]
I didn't skim product off the top, sir.
I didn't, I swear on my life.
Please believe me.
[breathing shakily]
So you're saying it wasn't you?
[exhales shakily]
Yes, it really wasn't me, okay?
Clean this up.
Yes, sir. I'm on it.
MILITARY SECURITY COMMAND
[typewriter keys clacking]
-Wanna have a cigarette?
-Sure, sir.
[grunts]
Mmm.
-Mmm, mmm.
-Thanks.
How's the office? Settling in?
Yes, sir. It's perfect.
It was just yesterday you were a captain,
and now you've already
been promoted again. Wow.
Time really flies.
-Well, you played a big part in that.
-Oh, come on, that's not true.
You earned it all yourself.
I don't know… [chuckles]
Didn't you say
you had a memorial service today?
Yes, sir. For my father.
[clicks tongue] Wrap up and head out.
Why are you still working?
I have a few more things to take care of.
I'll go once I'm finished.
I imagine you'll be
seeing your brother, right?
-Yes, sir.
-[chuckles]
The Busan situation… [licks lips]
…must keep him pretty busy, huh?
Well, I suppose so.
[Kitae] Here.
To your promotion.
-Thank you so much.
-[Soyeong chuckles softly]
Our Kihyun's a big man now, huh?
Lieutenant colonel already.
None of your classmates can say that.
STYLE
::cue()
Before you know it,
he'll be a general, don't you think?
-It's all because of you.
-Oh, please.
No, I barely lifted a finger. [chuckles]
You know, Kihyun, Kitae pulled
a lot of strings behind the scenes.
We owe everything we have to him,
you know.
This beautiful home, for instance.
You should really come by more often.
-We would love to have you--
-Soyeong.
Your food's getting cold.
Come on, aren't you gonna eat with us?
Do I have to keep feeding you like a baby?
-Say "ah."
-No, I'm too tired right now.
If you finish your dinner,
I'll read you a bedtime story later.
Come on.
Uncle Kihyun, I don't know
what a promotion is.
Hmm. It means I moved up in rank.
I'm a lieutenant colonel now.
What's "rank"?
Well, uh, you moved up
from first grade to second grade, right?
It's like that.
-Oh, so you went up higher?
-Mm-hmm.
Is Uncle Kitae more higher up than you,
or are you more higher up than him now?
[chuckles] He's much higher up than me.
General Hwang been good to you?
Now that you're working for him?
Yes.
Not giving you a hard time
because we're related?
Nobody is.
The colonel's been good to me too.
So, it's been fine.
Ahn Jaeho, right?
Military Academy graduate.
Yes.
I hear
that he's General Hwang's right-hand.
He mention me at all?
I don't believe he has.
Word is Hwang's been
gathering officers around him lately.
[Kihyun] He mostly meets with colonels
from the academy.
They drink, play golf.
He's made it clear he's a strong leader,
so lots of people follow him.
Just keep an eye on him, you got that?
Watch who joins his group
and track all his people.
Are you not…
comfortable with that?
No, I'm fine.
Kihyun, look.
You're my brother, hmm?
You know you can't be
in General Hwang's circle.
Of course. I'm aware.
Sorry, but,
who's General Hwang, Uncle Kihyun?
[Kihyun chuckles]
[phone ringing]
Yes, hello?
-A few more bites. Here.
-Just a minute.
Sorry, but it's Miss Choi.
-I'll take it downstairs.
-[Soyeong] Mmm.
Hi.
How did it go with Professor Jang?
Hold on a minute.
Soyeong, hang up.
-[clears throat]
-[phone cradle clicks]
We leave tomorrow.
Do you have everything ready?
Don't worry about that.
I just need you to make it on time.
[♪ intriguing music playing]
STYLE
::cue()
[Ikeda exhales]
[in Japanese] Father.
As for your successor,
have you decided yet?
It's Kimura, isn't it?
So,
you want me to step aside, too,
is that right?
[sighs]
No matter who the successor is,
I still can't leave things to you all yet.
So keep supporting me
and learning from me, hmm?
Stay here, by my side…
the same way you always have.
Hmm?
[Yuji chuckles softly]
Yes, I promise.
I'll always do whatever you tell me.
[Ikeda] Uh-huh.
I'll go get some tea.
Oh, sure. [chuckles]
[exhales deeply]
-[bell chimes]
-[monks chanting]
[Kitae] As fate would have it,
Chairman Ikeda died of cardiac arrest
at his residence that night.
[chanting continues]
[Kitae] Yakuza from all across Japan
attended the funeral.
And since the chairman died
without naming a successor,
speculation over
who would fill the power vacuum
became the center
of the mourners' attention.
[chanting continues in distance]
[grunts softly]
Okay, Professor.
Everything you saw in Korea?
Forget about it.
Erase it, you understand?
[in Japanese] And why don't you…
put in a good word with Harimoto
while you're at it.
[♪ somber music playing]
[bell chimes]
STYLE
::cue()
[bell chimes]
[camera shutters clicking]
That's enough! No more photos.
[crows cawing]
[Kitae, in Korean] In the end,
the Ikeda clan decided
to choose the next kumicho by vote.
Choi Yuji secured nine votes
out of the gate.
The question is will Harimoto stand by her
like he promised?
If so, the position would finally be hers.
[moderator, in Japanese]
The voting process is complete.
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
We will now count the ballots.
[in Korean] It's time.
They're counting ballots.
"Ikeda Yuji."
"Kimura Yoichi."
IKEDA YUJI - KIMURA YOICHI
Kimura Yoichi, ten votes.
Ikeda Yuji, nine votes.
Nineteen votes in total.
According to these results,
Kimura Yoichi is hereby named
the fourth kumicho of the Ikeda clan.
[applause]
STYLE
::cue()
[Kimura] How dare
this Korean mongrel whore…
aim to take full control of our clan.
Go on, drag her out of here before I do.
[♪ tense music playing]
[grunts softly]
[exhales]
[gulps]
[grunts softly]
[coughing]
You bitch! What'd you…
[grunts, splutters]
[gasping]
[groaning]
[whimpering, coughing]
Yuji! Yuji!
[coughing]
[grunting]
-[water splashing]
-[continues coughing]
Yuji!
Yuji…
[♪ dramatic music playing]
-[hammer cocks]
-[breathing heavily]
[yakuza member gasping]
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
[Kimura gasping, wheezing]
[Yuji grunts]
Listen, I'm kumicho now.
Are there any objections?
[all] We submit to you!
STYLE
::cue()
OCTOBER 26, 1979
[Kitae, in Korean] Meanwhile,
there was another group gathering
with their eyes
on their own kumicho's seat.
[slurps]
Hey, slow down. Quit drinking so much.
Director Cho, did you make it to Busan?
What did you find out about the protests?
It's just… students and normal people.
[chopsticks clatter]
They burned down a broadcasting station.
They're not just normal people.
[clears throat] Sir, listen.
We'd better take drastic measures
before these protests get worse.
This is no time to be talking
about martial law.
Busan and Masan aren't islands.
Who says it won't spread to the capital?
I know that! [clicks tongue]
That's why we need to crush them!
In Cambodia,
they killed three million people!
If we roll armor
over a couple million Reds,
would anyone care?
[sighs]
[Cho] You crazy son of a bitch,
I'm sick of your bullshit.
What?
[glass thuds]
You damn lunatic.
Keep talking like that
and you'll be the first to die.
-You little…
-[glass thuds]
[♪ tense music playing]
Director Cho, explain yourself.
Sir, listen.
The more you keep scum like this
by your side,
the sooner this country collapses.
What?
The good of our people should come first.
[cigarette sizzles]
Look at me.
You wanna be shot?
[knock on door]
[door opens]
You have a call, sir.
[door closes]
[sighs]
[Kitae] Sir.
Choi Yuji just made herself the kumicho.
It's not the time for that.
You need to get over here.
I've got a bad feeling.
[rain pattering]
Cho might be about
to pull something tonight.
Get here now.
I'm on my way.
[phone cradle clicks]
Gungjeong-dong. Now.
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
[clears throat, exhales]
[gunshots]
-Oh, shit. What the hell?
-[Kihun] Wh-what was that?
[gunfire]
-[Kihun gasps]
-[gunfire continues]
Wait, sir, be careful.
Damn it! Ah, shit.
STYLE
::cue()
Director.
-[gun clicking]
-[Cho] Son of a bitch!
Hey! Bring me your gun!
Ah, shit, come on!
The fucking thing's jammed!
Hey, why are all the lights out?
Sir?
It's pitch black.
How am I supposed to do this?
Please, tell me what's happening, sir.
Stay outside.
I'm gonna finish this once and for all.
Damn it.
Sir, uh… wh-what the hell's happening?
Beats me,
but whatever it is, we're screwed.
-[gunshot]
-[Kihun gasping]
Shit.
[gunshot]
On October 26th, 1979,
the kumicho, the boss,
the president of South Korea,
died.
[♪ suspenseful music playing]